IROTORI BAROKA

FULL STACK WFB DEVELOPER

birotori@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Medium

SUMMARY

Software Engineer | Full Stack Web Developer | Entrepreneur | Founder

Multi-skilled web developer with hands-on experience in developing and creating technology solutions for small businesses, using the Agile method and focused on customer satisfaction.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, Python, NumPy, Pandas, MongoDB, Firebase

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Agile Scrum

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer

May 2022 - Present

<u>Angel Help</u> — Spirituality platform. User can search an Angel to pray to get miracle or solution.

• Built with: React, Redux, MongoDB and Express API and Testing library

<u>Career APP</u> — Studying platform. User can connect, learn soft and professional skills and submit activities

Built with: React and Firebase Cloud

<u>YouMe</u> — A dating application to form couples. Users receive proposals and can like or decline. If two users match, they can write messages to each other.

• Built with: Ruby on Rails

MICROVERSE

Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

March 2022 - Present

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

AFRICA SAMURAI

Cotonou, Benin

Co-founder and Manager,

January 2018 - Present

• Thinking about the strategy of my company and managing operations and teams

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

March 2022 - November 2022

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

DIVE INTO CODE,

June 2020 - May 2022

Remote Full Stack Web Engender and Machine Learning, Full Time

- 720+ mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, Python, Colab, Pandas.
- Developed skill in remote working.